Preliminary Guide to the Residential Program Review Records, 1958 - 2002
Duke University. University Archives
Residential Program Review records 1958 - 2002
Duke University. Residential Program Review.
3.5 linear feet Extent: 3500 Items
Duke University. University Archives
The Residential Program Review began in 1998 to focus on residential improvements for upperclass students at Duke University. This administrative group oversaw the building of a new dormitory, the West-Edens Link, on Duke's West Campus, and continues to be involved in improving residential life on campus. Types of materials in the collection include reports, architectural drawings, proposals, surveys, correspondence, and minutes. Major subjects include architecture, living and social space, fraternities and sororities, residential policy, and residential issues of concern on the campus, such as alcohol abuse. English.
uaresprog
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Records of the University's Board of Trustees which have been existence for at least fifty years are available for scholarly research with the permission of the University Archivist. Access to records which have been in existence for less than fifty years shall be granted only by special permission, in writing, from the Board of Trustees.
Unprocessed materials are closed pending processing.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Residential Program Review Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 2000 (Accession number: A2000-45); 2003 (Accession number: A2003-4).
Historical Note
The Duke University Residential Program Review began in 1998 when Judith White, a former Special Assistant to the President, was appointed to direct the group. The Residential Program Review has focused on improving residential life on the West Campus for Duke's upperclass students. Their most important accomplishment was overseeing the completion of a new dormitory, the West-Edens Link, in 2002. The building offers housing, meeting and study rooms, and dining facilities. The Residential Program Review continues to work on improving other West Campus dormitories.
On the Residential Program Review website, <www.duke.edu/web/rdr>, the organization describes its mission as follows:
1. Provide residential space on Duke's historic West campus which is sufficient in amount and which has been maintained and upgraded in keeping with standards for comfortable, safe living quarters.
2. Create a climate for upperclass residential life consistent with the principles that have been articulated in all of our residential plans since 1994. Those principles are:
- support for intellectual and personal growth of our undergraduates
- equity of access and variety of experiences in the residential program
- building one diverse university community; and
- respect for Duke traditions of continuity and change, achieved by honoring past generations of students and faculty while preparing to serve students of the future.
Collection Overview
Collection includes reports, memoranda, correspondence, clippings, transparencies, and other materials related to residential planning at Duke University. Topics include architecture, living space, social space, fraternities and sororities, contemporary residential life issues, and surveys of student opinion. The items listed for each box are not folder titles, but instead offer a broad description of each box's contents. The files appear to be alphabetized but the collection is only preliminarily processed. Some materials are restricted.
Subject Headings
These and related materials may be accessed under the following subject headings in the Duke University Libraries online catalog.
College students -- Alcohol use -- North Carolina -- Durham; College students -- Alcohol use -- Prevention -- Planning; Dormitories -- United States; Duke University -- Administration; Duke University -- Buildings; Duke University. Residential Program Review; Duke University -- Students -- Attitudes; Duke University -- Students -- Social life and customs; Greek letter societies -- North Carolina -- Durham
Preliminary Description of the Collection
- Accession Number: A2000-45 (Box 1)
  - Presentations on Residential Plans for West Campus, 1999
  - Minutes of Steering Committee for Residential Programs, Board of Trustees, 1998-1999
  - Architectural Drawings, 1998-1999
  - Correspondence, Reports, Memoranda, Surveys, Agendas, and Objectives related to Residential Life, 1997-1999
- Accession Number: A2003-4 (Box 2)
  - Alcohol Issues, 1998-2000
  - Residential Life Clippings, 1958-2001
  - Residential Life Reports, 1972-1999
  - Architectural Plans, 1997-1999
  - "Devils' Desires" (student proposals), 1999-2000
  - Fraternity Issues and Concerns, 1998-1999
  - Residential Life Proposals, 1999-2000
  - Social Space Needs, 1999-2000
  - Surveys, 1999
  - Residential Programs Steering Committee minutes and other materials, 1998-2001 (Box 3)
  - Residential Life Reports, 1998
  - Memoranda, 1998
  - Residential Life Program Planning Background Materials (binder of collected information), 1994-2001
Related Material
Fraternities and Sororities collection
University Archives, Duke University.
Living Groups collection
University Archives, Duke University.